macmillan.org.uk 2007-06-30

# Privacy policy

The information you provide to us will be held on our computers, which are based in the UK. This privacy policy only relates to this Site and does not extend to your use of the internet outside of the Site (“ **Privacy Policy** ”). 

This Privacy Policy as amended from time to time describes the type of Personal Information collected and ways in which your Personal Information may be used. By visiting this Site, you accept the terms of this Privacy Policy and you consent to the use of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. All your Personal Information shall be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “ **Act** ”). If you want to know what Personal Information we collect and hold about you, please write to us at:- 

Data Protection Compliance Officer 

Macmillan Cancer Support 

89 Albert Embankment 

London SE1 7UQ 

Macmillan Cancer Support is the data controller of your Personal Information for the purposes of the Act. 

**What** **Personal Information do we collect?**

We will collect the Personal Information which you are required to provide to us during the registration process. You agree to supply us with accurate Personal Information. We may then use your Personal Information by publishing it on the Site to introduce sellers, suppliers and other users to you for the purpose of you getting what you want. 

By submitting Personal Information in an on-line document, email or otherwise, you consent to our use of the Personal Information for the purpose(s) for which it was provided (for example, to respond to your enquiry) and/or otherwise in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time submission, and for any additional purposes that are notified to you before, or at the time of, submitting Personal Information. We may also use your Personal Information including, without limit:- 

Information that you provide by filling in forms on this Site; 

Information about your computer including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type; 

Details of your visits to this Site and the pages and resources that you access; 

in the following ways:- 

To ensure that content from this Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and your computer; 

To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us; 

To notify you about changes to our services and to update your Personal Information; 

You may refuse to provide certain Personal Information; however the failure to provide requested Personal Information may result in your inability to use certain features of this Site. 

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. So, whilst we will do our best to protect your Personal Information, we cannot ensure the security of the Personal Information which you transmit to the Site. **Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your Personal Information we will use strict procedures and security features to prevent unauthorised access, but we cannot absolutely guarantee it will always kept completely secure because of the nature of the internet**. 

**Cookies**

We use alphanumeric identifiers (“ **cookies** ”) which are transferred to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser to enable our system to recognise your browser when you return to this Site and to monitor traffic patterns. You may modify your web browser to prevent it from accepting new cookies, to notify you when a cookie is received or to disable cookies entirely. Doing so, however, may prevent you from enjoying certain features of this Site. Find out more about Cookies by visiting [www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/). 

We use a type of cookie known as a "persistent" cookie. If you tick the 'Remember Me' box your email address and password will be saved in a cookie on this computer. This means that the next time you log on you will not need to re-enter these details. This cookie allows us to: 

  * welcome you as an individual when you log on to our website; 

In the future this cookie may: 

  * track where you have come from if you have come to our website from another website; and 

track how many times you visit a page. 

  * If you delete the cookie or your browser is set to not accept cookies this function will not work. For removing the 'Remember Me' cookie, just untick the 'Remember Me' box when you sign in. 

**Warning: we suggest you do not select the "Remember Me" function if you are using a shared computer or non-secure access.**

**What do we do with your Personal Information?**

We will use Personal Information to build up a profile of your interests and preferences.  When you supply us with your Personal Information tick the applicable box to give us permission to use your Personal Information for the purposes described next to the applicable box (e.g. if you would like to receive email newsletters or other information which may be of interest to you). We won’t give out your Personal Information unless you give us permission to do so by using the Site and ticking the relevant box for the specific purpose that you consent to when you submit your Personal Information or contemplate when using the Site. 

Apart from this, your Personal Information will not be disclosed to other third parties or used in any other way (other than as described in this Privacy Policy), unless we obtain your prior consent to use it in this way or we are required to do so by law. 

This Site does not target any person under 18 (referred to as “ **children** ” or “ **child** ”) and our requests for Personal Information are not directed at children. We do not intentionally collect Personal Information from children. If registration or other Personal Information provided through this Site reveals that the visitor is a child, we will not allow that child to continue to provide Personal Information and any Personal Information provided to that point will be deleted from our records. 

**Disclosing your Personal Information to third parties**

We may disclose your Personal Information to third parties: 

If you inadvertently or otherwise disclose any personally identifiable information in a posting or upload or submit any content which may be offensive or in breach of this Agreement and/or any Content Standards to contact you and discuss with or notify you its removal or amendment (we reserve the right however to remove and/or suspend any material which you post without notice and any reason at our discretion). 

In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets we may disclose your Personal Information to the buyer or seller of such business or assets; 

To pass your Personal Information to our affiliates or certain suppliers/sub-contractors to supply goods, services or information requested by you; 

If we are under a duty to disclose or share your Personal Information to comply with any legal obligation or to enforce or apply our terms and conditions and other agreements or protect our rights or property, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction; 

Such as advertisers (for the purpose of serving advertisements), suppliers, potential suppliers and our potential customers and those of our affiliated companies with details about our services, but we will not provide them with any information which can be used to identify you. 

  * You have the right to request us not to use your Personal Information in this way by indicating before submitting your Personal Information whether you mind your Personal Information being used in this way. Alternatively, you can exercise your right to do so by contacting [webmanager@macmillan.org.uk](mailto:webmanager@macmillan.org.uk) or by writing to us at the address at the beginning of this Privacy Policy. 
  * Please note: by posting any Personal Information on a listing or otherwise in any publicly accessible area of the Site, such information may be collected by third parties over which we have no control. **We strongly recommend all Registered User Areas are intended to keep postings anonymous** (other than where you have granted limited access to an Online Diary and you have taken a positive decision to make Personal Information available to those people to whom you have given access to your Online Diary).   We are not responsible for the use of such information by such third parties.

**Please therefore exercise all due care and consideration before disclosing any Personal Information that will be disclosed on public areas or in your Online Diary. You should also avoid disclosing any Personal Information that may be used to identify you (such as you name, age, home or work address or name of your employer) especially if you disclose any sensitive Personal Information such as:**

  * racial or ethnic origin; 
  * political beliefs; 
  * philosophical or religious beliefs; 
  * membership of a trade union or political party; 
  * physical or mental health; 
  * sexual life; or 
  * the commission of criminal offences or proceedings. 

**Contact Us**

You may contact us via email at [webmanager@macmillan.org.uk](mailto:webmanager@macmillan.org.uk)or phone at 020 7840 7840 if you do not want your Personal Information to be used in a certain way, if you wish to review Personal Information on our records, if you need to correct your Personal Information, or if you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy.
